# Karanguptage

# Fullstack developer, Block chain, shopify expert

@ karan.guptage@gmail.com Parantford, Ontario Canada



#### **SUMMARY**

Senior Full Stack Developer who has possessed various web backend & frontend languages/frameworks and blockchain technology with over 7 years of experience in requirements gathering, analysis, design, implementation, maintenance of software applications and testing Client/Server and Web applications. Demonstrated ability to satisfy upper management through reliability, commitment, and problem resolution.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Full stack Developer, Shopify, Block chain

(Remote)

**=** 12/2022 - 09/2024

- Developed and launched a robust website using MERN Stack and TypeScript, demonstrating proficiency in full-stack development.
- Built proprietary nodes on both Ethereum and Binance blockchain networks for effective data analysis, demonstrating deep understanding of blockchain technology.
- Successfully deployed the website on Amazon Web Services(AWS), howcasing competency in cloud platforms and deployment protocols.
- Lead the development team in establishing an infrastructure that enables realtime data retrieval from proprietary nodes, showcasing leadership skills and understanding of real-time data processing.

## Back end Developer

(Remote)

**=** 05/2016 - 11/2022

- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured hightraffic, page views, and User Experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales revenue.
- Oversaw full lifecycle of software development for various projects.
- Designed processes for cleanup and performance improvement, that minimized downtime by 13%.

## Front end Engineer

(Remote)

**#** 09/2012 - 04/2016

- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed.
- Collaborate with senior level usability specialists and technology/business leaders to interpret requirements into interactive experiences.
- Conduct research and developed creative processes by sharing new trends and development technologies with other designers.

# **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor's degree - Information Technology

University of Alberta

**#** 2008 - 08/2012

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Node.j	s Full st	Full stack Development		Next.js
PHP	Laravel	Django	Python	_
Javascript/Typescript			ordPress	
Mongo	DB MyS	SQL Co	deigniter	Dart

#### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

## Achieving 99% user satisfaction

We have achieved great customer satisfaction through sophisticated implementation of the front-end and have realized more than 20 projects. We have increased the agency's monthly profit to \$150,000.

#### Exceeded throughput target by 90%

Collaborate well with teammates, use cloud-based workflows to reduce task completion time by 80% every time, and successfully complete more than 92% of tasks.

## **Expanding corporate profits**

Discovered new clients, negotiated over \$5 Million of partnership and product deals with key customers based on insights gathered in product development

# Breaking records in sales rankings

By realizing e-commerce with a neat, friendly, and sophisticated face-to-face structure and a highconversion logical structure, we achieved the secondhighest sales ranking throughout the year.

CY Enhancy